# OGAMBA PATRICK JUNIOR

Software Engineer, Mobile Developer, FullStack Developer

### Contact

#### **Address:**

Carrefour Nouvelle Route Cite Sic, Douala, Cameroon

#### **Phone Number:**

+ 237 670157564

#### **Email:**

ogambapatrickjunior@gmail.com

## Languages

- English
- French

# Education

### **Software Engineering**

- University Institute of the Golf of Guinee (IUG).

## Socials

#### **MY PORTFOLIO**

Click to Visit

#### **GITHUB**

- PatrickJunior007

### LINKEDIN

- Patrick Junior

### Certifications

- Higher National Diploma (HND) in Software Engineering.
- Bachelor Degree in Software Engineering.

## Summary

Software Engineer with two years of experience, I successfully combined my studies with work and other commitments showing myself to be self-motivated, organized and capable of working in collaboration with others. In addition to that I'm very hardworking, learn quickly and easily.

# Skills Highlights

### Software Engineer 09/2021 till present

- Have skills in Graphic Designing.
- Experienced in modeling of applications.
- Well-versed in web development tools including HTML, CSS, JQuery, WordPress, Bootstrap.
- Experienced in Search Engine Optimization (SEO).
- Skilled in programming languages such as PHP, MySQL, and JavaScript.
- Skilled in React Native, React and Vue/Nuxt Js Framework.
- Clear and understanding knowledge in the versioning tools Git and GitHub.
- Skilled in the PHP backend framework **Laravel** for web application development.
- Skilled in developing REST APIs using Laravel, Node and Express.
- Other Skills: MongoDB, FireBase, TypeScript, Testing, Cucumber, Cypress.

# Experience

### Software Engineer (01/03/2022 - Present)

- NKAP SARL, Douala Cameroon
  - Worked on several web applications using technologies like Nuxt/Vue JS, React, PHP, Laravel and WordPress.
  - Took part in testing and automating web applications and software using technologies like Cypress and Cucumber.
  - Took part in the Development of Mobile applications using React Native, TypeScript, Expo RN, REST APIs and Firebase.
  - Integration of RESTFUL APIs in both web and mobile applications.
  - Worked on the SEO of several clients' websites.
  - Collaboration with UI/UX designers to improve user interfaces and designs.

### Frontend Developer (19/09/2021 – 29/12/2021)

- SIKATRONIC GROUP, Douala Cameroon
  - Using technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap.
  - Collaboration with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability, experience and design.

### Intern (19/09/2020 – 19/01/2021)

- 237SOFT, Douala Cameroon
  - Took part into projects connected with both Web app, App development and Modeling.